Before we get into some specific examples of housework a couple of tips to keep in mind.
在我们进入一些具体的家务示例之前，请记住一些技巧。
And this is something that I always have to remind myself as well when I'm describing a process maybe
当我描述一个过程时，这也是我总是要提醒自己的事情
I'm giving instructions to someone for how to do something.
我正在向某人指示如何做某事。
Maybe over the phone or I'm explaining the kind of things I regularly have to do kind of like a routine.
也许是通过电话，或者我在解释我经常要做的事情，有点像例行公事。
I always remember to tell a story so that doesn't mean I need to add a bunch of fake stuff but what
我总是记得讲一个故事，所以这并不意味着我需要添加一堆虚假的东西，而是什么
it means is I want to connect it together and make it personal.
这意味着我想将它连接在一起并使其个性化。 如果我只是说然后做这个然后做这个然后做这个然后做这个是非常枯燥的。
I do try to think about using different types of sentences to keep the syntax interesting.
我确实尝试考虑使用不同类型的句子来保持语法的趣味性。
I also think about making sure to sometimes maybe add a little bit of emotion.
我还考虑确保有时可能会添加一点情感。
Sometimes I will add a description of something maybe I'm doing in a little bit more detail but I try
有时我会添加对某事的描述，也许我正在做的更详细一点，但我会尝试
to make it feel as much like I can like a simple story.
让它感觉就像我喜欢一个简单的故事。
And when I think about it in this way it helps me I think explain what I want to explain clearly so
当我以这种方式思考它时，它会帮助我解释清楚我想要解释的内容
that the other person the person listening to me gets it immediately and doesn't miss out on the details.
听我的人立即得到它并且不会错过细节。
If it's kind of interesting.
如果有点意思的话。
If it's kind of interesting then people will probably like to listen to what you have to say.
如果它有点有趣，那么人们可能会喜欢听你说什么。
So make it personal make it a story number to use the present tense just like when we're giving a routine
所以让它变得个人化，让它成为一个故事编号，使用现在时，就像我们在例行公事时一样
we're talking about activities that usually happen.
我们谈论的是通常发生的活动。
So use the present tense because that makes it a lot easier.
所以使用现在时，因为这样会更容易。
You can focus on your sentence structure you can focus on using the right words you can focus on maybe
你可以专注于你的句子结构 你可以专注于使用正确的词 你可以专注于也许
making it a little bit interesting what you're describing what you have to do regularly because you're
让你描述的事情变得有点有趣，你必须经常做的事情，因为你是
not thinking about do I need to make that in the past I don't know that makes it a lot easier.
不考虑我是否需要在过去做这件事，我不知道这会让事情变得容易得多。
So just use the present tense.
所以只用现在时。 只需使用现在时。
OK those are two things I want you to remember.
好的，这是我希望你记住的两件事。
Now let's look at an example of chores specifically laundry.
现在让我们看一个专门洗衣的家务示例。